Guide to the John Latimer papers, 1890-1990 MS0370.UA
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
John Latimer papers
1890-1991
1944-1980
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
MS0370.UA
9.5 Linear Feet
John Francis Latimer (1903-1991) was a Professor of Classics and University Marshal at The George Washington University. Collection include books, correspondence, articles, notes, photographs, syllabi, audio tapes, reports, newsletters, speeches, and lantern slides. They range in date from 1890-1990.
Restrictions on Access
Some records may be restricted.
Acquisition Information
The collection was donated to the University Archives in two accessions by John Latimer in 1987 and John Ziolkowski (Professor of Classics at GW) in 2000.
Biographical Note
John Francis Latimer (1903-1991) was a Professor of Classics and University Marshal at The George Washington University. He was born in Clinton, Mississippi in 1903. He graduated from Clinton High School in 1918 and from Mississippi College with an A.B. degree in 1922. Dr. Latimer earned an A.M. degree from the University of Chicago in 1926 and a Ph.D. in Classics from Yale University in 1929. In 1964 Mississippi College awarded him the honorary Doctor of Literature.
John Latimer was a teacher, coach, and principal at Clinton High School in Clinton, Mississippi from 1922-24, and instructor in Classics at Vanderbilt University from 1926-27. He went on to teach Greek at the Taft School in Watertown, Connecticut from 1929-31, was assistant professor of Classic, Knox College in Galesburgh, Illinois from 1931-33, and professor of Classics at Drury College, Springfield, Missouri from 1933-36. He came to GW in 1936 and, except for five years during World War II, when he won four Battle Stars for Distinguished Service with the U.S. Navy, spent the rest of his career there.
Dr. Latimer became a Full Professor in 1954, and Professor Emeritus of Classics in 1973. During Dr. Latimer tenure at the University he served as chair of the Classics Department from 1936-71, continuing to teach until 1973. He was Assistant Dean, College of General Studies from 1951-56. He also served as Assistant, then Associate Dean of Faculties from 1956-64. Dr. Latimer became the Director, Foreign Student Affairs in 1964, a position he held until 1966. In addition to these various duties, he also served as University Marshal from 1953-69.
After Dr. Latimer's retirement he continued to serve the University as President of the Friends of the Libraries (1977-78) and as a founder and President of the Society of the Emeriti (1978-91). In a career distinguished by offices of great service to The George Washington University as well as to numerous professional organizations, he gained a national reputation for his devotion to the cause of Classical League (where he served as President from 1960-66).
Dr. Latimer published over 125 articles on classical subjects and What's Happened to our High Schools, a book on the history of the high school curriculum. He prepared a new, special Bicentennial edition of Glass's A Life of George Washington in Latin Prose. Continuing his military service he attained the rank of Captain in the U.S. Naval Reserve. Dr. Latimer possessed great personal charm and generosity and was a friend and counselor to countless students and friends.
The John Francis Latimer Prize in Classics was established in 1973 and is awarded to a graduating senior who has made the most outstanding record as a major in the Department of Classics. Dr. Latimer died in 1991.
N.B. This history note was written in 2005
Collection Scope and Content
Materials in this collection include books, correspondence, articles, notes, photographs, syllabi, audio tapes, reports, newsletters, speeches, and lantern slides. They range in date from 1890-1990.
Collection Organization
Organized in two series.
Audiotapes; Photographs; Speeches; Reports and dissertations; Classical languages; Lantern slides; Washington (D.C.); Latimer, John Francis; George Washington University
- Personal papers, 1944-1988; MS0370 Series 1; 9.0 Linear feet (Box 19, Box 13)
  Scope and Contents note
  This series consists of biographical information, Society of the Emeriti, teaching materials, materials on the study of Latin and Greek in secondary and higher education. The material dates from 1944-88.
  - Class 1897, Correspondence, Stats, Photos, 1917-1942 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Record Books, 1890-1910 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Address Cards, undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Miscellaneous, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - "The Prime Need of Mississippi", undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - "Claims for an Order of American Knighthood", undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Documents relating to Webb Family, 1915-1920 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Play - "The Truce", undated (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Notebook on Classical World, undated (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1944-1948 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 1944-1946 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 1914-1945 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Life of GW in Latin Prose - photocopy, undated (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Vocabulary, undated (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Final Report, Glass Report with NEH and GW, undated (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Transcripts of GW's Life Translation, undated (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Transcripts of GW's Life Translation, undated (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Transcripts of GW's Life Translation, undated (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - The Case for Basic Education - Book, undated (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Rays of Hope - Book, undated (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Human Being and Citizen - Book, undated (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - We see by the Papers, undated (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - St. John's Child Development Center-Trustees, 1968-1970 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Technology and Human Values, 1965-1970 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Study of Graduate Programs in Classical studies at U of Missouri, 1966 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - University resident Theater Association-Correspondence, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence to Sen. Barry Goldwater, 1969 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Open Court Publishing Co., 1969-1972 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Institute of Man and Science, 1973-1974 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Council for Basic Education, 1968-1974 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - American Council for Learned Societies and related Material, 1959-1971 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - National Committees for Latin and Greek, 1967-1987 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Foreign Student affairs and GW, 1964-1966 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Classical High School in Arlington, 1972-1973 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Comites Thomae Mori Organization, 1972-1972 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Washington Honors School, 1965-1966 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Bicentennial Classical Institute, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - American School for Classical Studies in Athens, 1968-1972 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Classical Association of the Atlantic States Inc., 1967 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Undergraduates in foreign Languages, 1974 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - American Classical League and JCL memberships, 1963-1969 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Education in America - press report, 1963 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Articles justifying Classical study, 1964-1969 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 1966-1970 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - American Council on Education, 1954-1964 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - National Humanities Faculty, 1968-1969 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Conference on Humanities programs-Correspondence, 1952-1975 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - "Teaching of Latin" The Encyclopedia of Education, 1967-1970 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - The American Council on the teaching of Foreign Languages, 1966-1972 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Miscellaneous, 1953-1967 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Teaching Methods - Latin, 1957-1967 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Classical Study in U.S., 1963-1989 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Validity of Classical Study, 1963-1970 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Validity of Classical Study, 1966-1969 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - American Classical League, 1962-1987 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Letter Draft Sent to Philantropie foundations, 1969-1970 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Language Articles, 1940-1970 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - International Congress of Classical Studies, 1964-1969 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - International Classical Studies, 1964 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Miscellaneous, 1919-1972 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Latin Conference, 1970 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Survey of Latin in Private Schools, 1987 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Latin in Alexandria, VA public elementary schools, 1972 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Latin in elementary schools- NEH founded films relating to, 1970 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Latin texts, Articles leading to publication of, 1967-1968 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Letters to editors - published, 1952-1969 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Letters to editors - unpublished, 1978-1990 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - American Classics League Newsletter, 1965-1975 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Airlie House Conference, 1965 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Faculty evaluations- Classics Dept., 1965-1966 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Departmental appointments, 1967-1968 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Miscellaneous, 1965-1973 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - General Correspondence, 1966-1969 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence- students, 1966-1972 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Report of the Registrar, 1968-1969 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Faculty Recommendations, 1964-1968 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - G.W. Foundation, 1958-1967 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Report, Columbian College, 1963-1965 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Chronology, Columbian College, 1790-1873 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Student Recommendations, 1965-1973 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Examinations, 1968-1969 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Interview reports of fellowship application (east-west center, Hawaii), 1966-1969 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - television programs, 1963-1964 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence regarding Positions, 1968-1973 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence, Dr. Laura Somner, 1965-1972 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Obituaries, 1966-1969 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Meyer Pavilion- G.W. Hospital, 1966 (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Correspondence, Personal, 1953-1983 (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - Correspondence, Classics Dept., 1965-1978 (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - American Council of Learned Societies, 1968-1969 (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - President Elliott, 1965 (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - Articles relating to Bilingual Teaching and Textbooks, 1953 (Box 7, Folder 23)
  - Latin in High schools - articles and Correspondence, 1953-1954 (Box 7, Folder 24)
  - Bilingual Latin course "Pong express", 1952-1973 (Box 7, Folder 25)
  - Unanswered Correspondence Survey, 1954-1955 (Box 7, Folder 26)
  - Response to Survey, 1952-1955 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1954-1955 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Editorials and Articles, 1953-1968 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - What's Happened to our High Schools? reviews and letters., 1958 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Summary tables, undated (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - William Volker Fund, 1953-1955 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Vergilian Society, 1937-1967 (Box 8, Folder 7.1)
  - Experimental Seminar- NEH funded "Classics and the Goals for America", 1971 (Box 8, Folder 7.2)
  - Life of GW in Latin Prose, 1977 (Box 8, Folder 7.3)
  - Correspondence and grant expenses for Life of GW, 1975-1977 (Box 8, Folder 7.4)
  - Correspondences relating to trans. of Life of GW, 1975-1988 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Reviews of Life of GW, 1978 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Research Materials relating to Life of GW, 1824-1975 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Life of GW - Sales slips, 1976-1978 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Sales slips - Glass Trilogy, 1977-1979 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Faculty Correspondence, 1965-1976 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - The Oxford Conference, 1966-1967 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Course Syllabi, 1963-1969 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Intro. to Life of GW in Latin Prose, 1976 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - English/ Latin Liturgy, 1968 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Latin in America's Public High Schools Dissertation, 1974 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - GW memorial fund reception, 1976-1978 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Society of the Emeriti, 1978-1987 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Society of the Emeriti, 09/1990 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Society of the Emeriti, 1989-1990 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Society of the Emeriti, 08/1988 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Society of the Emeriti, 1987-07/1988 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Society of the Emeriti, 08/06/1980 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Society of the Emeriti Summer, 1983 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Society of the Emeriti, 1978-1985 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Society of the Emeriti, 1981-1982 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Society of the Emeriti, 1982-1983 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Society of the Emeriti, 06/1989-06/1990 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Thebaid 1. 1-144. Translation Excerpt, undated (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - "A Life of George Washington in Latin Prose" Copyright certificates, undated (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - "A Life of George Washington in Latin Prose", undated (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, 01/1989-12/1990 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Tape: Spoken Greek Basic Course, undated (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Tape: Classics: Oedipus Knox Lecture, undated (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Tape: The First Family University Colloquium, undated (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Tape: Knox Lecture #8- The Bacchae, undated (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Tape: Knox Lecture #3,#5,#7- The Oristeia, undated (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - The Antigone, Elektra 11, undated (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Books: Interlinear Greek-English. "A New Testament", undated (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - The Making of Latin by Conway, undated (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Analysis Philologica and Novi Testamenti Graeci, undated (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Ecclesiastical Greek for Beginners by J.E. Lowe, undated (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - The New Testament, undated (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - Trade Union Pension Systems by Latimer, undated (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - Syntax of Classical Greek by Basil Lanneau Gilversleeve, undated (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - Sophocles by Dindorf, undated (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - The Birds by Aristophanes, Tr. W.W. Merry, undated (Box 12, Folder 15)
  - The Philoctetes of Sophocles by Graves, undated (Box 12, Folder 16)
  - Biblioteca Universale di Scelta Litterature Anticae Moderna, undated (Box 12, Folder 17)
  - Straboniis Geographica, undated (Box 12, Folder 18)
  - Greek Testament - Rare book in box, undated (Box 12, Folder 19)
  - Greek Testament - in box, undated (Box 12, Folder 20)
  - Industrial Pension Systems, vols. 1, 2 by Latimer, undated (Box 12, Folder 21)
  - The American Almanac, undated (Box 12, Folder 22)
  - 1 notebook, undated (Box 12, Folder 23)
  - Vergilio Nell Epigrafia Pompeiana, undated (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Mock-up. A Grammatical and Historical Supplemental to a Life of GW, undated (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Mock-up. A Composite Translation of a Life of GW in Latin Prose, undated (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Preliminary Leaves 29 pp, xix-xv chapt. summaries of a Bio. of Washington in Latin Prose, undated (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - The Washington Classical Society Incorporation and Tax Exempt status, 1963-1968 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - The Washington Classical Society, undated (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - The Washington Classical Club, undated (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Kaufman, Erich. "Grundfragen des kunftligen Reichsverfassung.", undated (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Xeroxed chapter contents from an unidentified book on Ancient education, undated (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Various articles on teaching Latin, undated (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Educational Research Bulletin. Prof. Francis Glass, Master Teacher by R.H. Ekelberry, undated (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Classical Philology. Drs. Oost and Kaster. Correspondence, undated (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Dorothea Gray. Cassette and Oral History interview. Francis Scott Key Bookshop during WW II, undated (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Saturday Review, undated (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - George Sandy's Ovid, undated (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - George Sandy's Ovid (cont.), undated (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Review of Sorey's: The Unity of Plato's Thought., undated (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Shorey, Paul-Plato, The Republic with an English translation and critique by Dr. Latimer -The Case of the Classics, undated (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - English and the Classics. Paper by Craig Thompson, undated (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - New Deal and Old Rome, undated (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - American Classical Scholarship and Caleb Alexander by Dr. Latimer, undated (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Bernal's "Blacks", Herodotus and other classical evidence by Frank M. Snowden Jr. Romans and Blacks, a review by Frank M. Snowden, Jr., undated (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Plato's Apology, undated (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - The Classical Investigation. Part One: general report abridged Ed., undated (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - Some Early American Latin Textbooks and Teaching Methods (Portions of a Paper), undated (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - America fom the Foreign Point of View, undated (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Battle of the Books. Education in Democracy, undated (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Biographical Memoirs. Harold and Ruth From, undated (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - The Classical Outlook, undated (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence with Harold and Ruth From, undated (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - The Book of the Dead, undated (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - The American Classical League. Meetings Programs, undated (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - Report of the Committee on Secondary Schools Studies, 07/09/1892 (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - Miscellaneous, undated (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - Index cards of members to American Classic League, undated (Box SHARED Box 21, Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Labels of historical sites and cites (Ancient to Renaissance), undated (Box SHARED Box 21, Box 17, Folder 2)
  - School masters of Colonial Boston, undated (Box SHARED Box 21, Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Miscellaneous book titles, undated (Box SHARED Box 21, Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Francis Glass Translation of "A life of George Washington" e.d by: John Latimer, undated (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - (Book) A life of George Washington in Latin Prose: by Francis Glass, A.M of Ohio, undated (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - (Book) A Grammatical and Historical Supplement to "A life of George Washington" in Latin Prose: By Francis, AM of Ohio, undated (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - (Picture) Dr. Letterman, undated (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - Reel to Reel: "Decade of Crisis" and "Lectures in Miniature", 1962 (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Reel to Reel: Steve Allison Show and Sesquicentinnial Convocation, 1971 (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - Reel to Reel: St. Stephen's School, 1963 (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - Reel to Reel: Miss Edith Hamilton, n.d., undated (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - Reel to Reel: New Trends in Latin Pt. 1 and 2, n.d., undated (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - Reel to Reel: Edith Hamilton Speech, 1960; talk at Albany, 1964, 1960-1964 (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - Reel to Reel: Teen Talk, Education and the Pursuit of Culture, 1961 -1963 (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - Reel to Reel: Talks given at ACL-APA meeting in Cincinnati, 1971 (Box 19, Folder 8)
  - Reel to Reel: Wakefield High School Speech, 1961; Anna Russell--Folk Songs and Hamlet (Box 19, Folder 9)
  - Reel to Reel: Steve Allison Show, 1964 (Box 19, Folder 10)
  - Reel to Reel: Talk by Dr. Else, n.d., undated (Box 19, Folder 11)
  - Reel to Reel: LeBovit Address, 06/19/1967 (Box 19, Folder 12)
  - Reel to Reel: Hoover on War, Channel XXI, 1970 (Box 19, Folder 13)
  - Cassette/Analogue Tapes: Dr. Carroll Quigley, professor of History, Georgetown University,(3 tapes), 02/09/1971 (Box 19, Folder 14)
  - Cassette/Analogue Tapes: Quincy Luncheon, GWU Marvin Center, 04/16/1989 (Box 19, Folder 15)
  - Cassette/Analogue Tapes: Dr. Bernard Knox on Greek Tragedy, (2 tapes), 03/16/1971 (Box 19, Folder 16)
  - Cassette/Analogue Tapes: Dr. Quigley, 02/10/1971 (Box 19, Folder 17)
  - Cassette/Analogue Tapes: Dr. C. Forbes, n.d. (2 tapes), undated (Box 19, Folder 18)
  - Cassette/Analogue Tapes: Monday night lecture, 04/03/1989 (Box 19, Folder 19)
  - Cassette/Analogue Tapes: Dr. Thelma Hunt, SOTE luncheon, 3/21/1986 (Box 19, Folder 20)
  - Cassette/Analogue Tapes: Prof. Hood, Oxford n.d., undated (Box 19, Folder 21)
  - Cassette/Analogue Tapes: Joe Schork, 05/13/1972 (Box 19, Folder 22)
  - Cassette/Analogue Tapes: Ted Buttrey [or Buttrick], "Oedipus Rex and Antigone" n.d., undated (Box 19, Folder 23)
  - Cassette/Analogue Tapes: School Admin. look at classics, missing tape, undated (Box 19, Folder 24)
  - Cassette/Analogue Tapes: Dr. T. Buttrey, Adventures of Jason and Odysseus, undated (Box 19, Folder 25)
  - Cassette/Analogue Tapes: Dr. Knox, Bacchal, undated (Box 19, Folder 26)
  - Cassette/Analogue Tapes: Dr. Knox, Oedipus Rex, undated (Box 19, Folder 27)
  - Cassette/Analogue Tapes: Dr. Knox, Antigone, Medea, undated (Box 19, Folder 28)
  - Cassette/Analogue Tapes: Dr. Gerald F. Else; and Sequincentennial Convocation: Pres. Elliott confering degrees, undated (Box 19, Folder 29)
  - Cassette/Analogue Tapes: GW Translation, 03/03/1977 (Box 19, Folder 30)
  - Cassette/Analogue Tapes: Talk on Glass, 02/21/1978 (Box 19, Folder 31)
  - Cassette/Analogue Tapes: Edward Everett (1794-1865), 11/20/1979 (Box 19, Folder 32)
  - Cassette/Analogue Tapes: Edward Everett (1794-1865), 11-10-1979 (Box 19, Folder 33)
  - Cassette/Analogue Tapes: Cecil Johnson and John Latimer at Chapel Hill, 04/1972 (Box 19, Folder 34)
  - Cassette/Analogue Tapes: Remarks at Breakfast for Class of 1922 n.d., undated (Box 19, Folder 35)
  - Cassette/Analogue Tapes: California Classical Association dinner, 1973 (Box 19, Folder 36)
  - Cassette/Analogue Tapes: Talks, 1985 (Box 19, Folder 37)
  - Cassette/Analogue Tapes: Notes on Latin Texts, 07/1975 (Box 19, Folder 38)
  - Cassette/Analogue Tapes: Ant. Soc; notes on class texts, 06/30/1975 (Box 19, Folder 39)
  - Cassette/Analogue Tapes: Sept. 17, VA Beach, undated (Box 19, Folder 40)
  - Cassette/Analogue Tapes: James P. McCoy, USS Quincy, undated (Box 19, Folder 41)
  - Cassette/Analogue Tapes: Quincy, 09/16/1978 (Box 19, Folder 42)
  - Cassette/Analogue Tapes: 16 Sept, Springfield, MO, undated (Box 19, Folder 43)
  - Cassette/Analogue Tapes: Virginia Beach--Woodie Jaffe, and others, 09/17/1977 (Box 19, Folder 44)
  - Cassette/Analogue Tapes: De Angelis--Castell Memorial Service, 10/16/1980 (Box 19, Folder 45)
  - Cassette/Analogue Tapes: Dean Harper; Dean Haysen's "Swan Song", 05/02/1984 (Box 19, Folder 46)
  - Cassette/Analogue Tapes: Cosmos Club, 04/03/1989 (Box 19, Folder 47)
  - Cassette/Analogue Tapes: Excerpts from newscasts of events on MAYDAY, 05/3/1971 (Box 19, Folder 48)
  - Text: "A Life of George Washington, in Latin Prose", Francis Glass n.d. (3 copies), undated (Box 19, Folder 49)
  - Text: A Composite Translation of "A Life of George Washington, in Latin Prose", 1976 (Box 19, Folder 50)
  - Text: Leaflet: "Corinth: a Brief History of the City and a Guide to the Excavations", 1964 (Box 19, Folder 51)
  - Glass Slides: Taormina Theater, undated (Box 19, Folder 52)
  - Glass Slides: Taorimina street scene, undated (Box 19, Folder 53)
  - Glass Slides: Unknown coastal scene, undated (Box 19, Folder 54)
  - Glass Slides: Map of ancient Syracuse, undated (Box 19, Folder 55)
  - Glass Slides: Sylla, undated (Box 19, Folder 56)
  - Glass Slides: Arethusa--Syracuse, undated (Box 19, Folder 57)
  - Glass Slides: Syracuse--theater, undated (Box 19, Folder 58)
  - Glass Slides: Latomia, Cappuccini, Syaracuse, undated (Box 19, Folder 59)
  - Glass Slides: Cappuchini, Syracuse, undated (Box 19, Folder 60)
  - Glass Slides: H.R. Labyrinth, Pompei, undated (Box 19, Folder 61)
  - Glass Slides: Pompei--Hall of Fauk, undated (Box 19, Folder 62)
  - Glass Slides: Unknown-- (Pompei?), undated (Box 19, Folder 63)
  - Glass Slides: Unknown--amphitheater, undated (Box 19, Folder 64)
  - Glass Slides: Lararium--Pompei, undated (Box 19, Folder 65)
  - Glass Slides: Street of Tombs--Pompei, undated (Box 19, Folder 67)
  - Glass Slides: Smoking Vesuvius from Pompei, undated (Box 19, Folder 68)
  - Glass Slides: Herculaneum, new excavation, undated (Box 19, Folder 69)
  - Glass Slides: Herculaneum, new excavation, undated (Box 19, Folder 70)
  - Glass Slides: Temple of Neptune--Paestum, undated (Box 19, Folder 71)